MONTGOMERY FLAGG

(831) 236-3989 monteflagg@gmail.com Los Angeles, CA PORTFOLIO GITHUB LINKEDIN

ABOUT

Following a 15-year career in customer experience at companies such as Apple, Hulu, and Compass, and a decade of co-founding and operating a tech startup, I decided to invest in my personal growth by returning to school to enhance my technical knowledge and pursue a new career path. After gaining a year of experience as a software engineer, I identified a deep-seated passion for product management. This realization was prompted by my desire to not only bring my technical expertise, but also leverage my design creativity, customer empathy, emotional intelligence, problem-solving, and general product acumen to an organization.

ENTREPRENUER EXPERIENCE

<u>Equation Travel LLC.</u> - Lodging and Experience Booking Engine Startup

Denver, CO (Remote)

Oct. 2021 - Present

Co-Founder | Product Lead & User Experience Designer

- Established and directed the product vision, strategy, and user experience for web and mobile platforms, focusing on creating an innovative booking solution to facilitate connections between travelers and independent lodging providers.
- Defined the product roadmap based on comprehensive user stories, divided into three distinct stages, and consisting of various partners and milestones. This approach was designed to achieve ideal product-market fit, promote user adoption and engagement, and ultimately provide a better booking solution for lodging owners.
- Collaborated with a team of contracted Engineers, conducted extensive research to identify and select a suitable API provider for hotel rates, availability, and content, and spearheaded development stages to deliver the MVP.

Pheebo Inc. - Mobile App Development and Management Startup

Los Angeles, CA

Co-Founder | Product Lead

Jan. 2012 - Dec 2019

- Procured, managed, and shipped seven app development and design contracts generating over \$500k in gross revenue in categories including but not limited to food ordering, CRM, e-commerce, educational gaming, and video entertainment.
- Interviewed, hired, and managed engineers and designers involved in each mobile project, fostering strong partnerships and aligning goals to ensure optimal customer satisfaction and smooth product development and execution.
- Launched flagship product PheeboTV on iOS and AppleTV App stores, designed to enhance the user experience of discovering, enjoying, and sharing online video entertainment, driving over 120,000 downloads.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Unit21 Inc.
San Francisco, CA (Remote)

Software Engineer Aug. 2022 - Present

- Refactored legacy code to update application logic tightly coupled to an Object Relational Mapping (ORM) to be database agnostic, by helping implement an object service that adds support for document-based databases such as MongoDB.
- Collaborated with engineering leads and cross-functional teams to design and engineer DataDog dashboards, monitors, and alerts to achieve 100% coverage of Service Level Agreement (SLA) and Service Level Objective (SLO) targets.
- Developed and integrated new internal API routes and extended the coverage of customer-facing API route tests, elevating overall testing coverage from 50% to 98%.

QA Analyst | Technical Support

Jan. 2022 - July 2022

- Expanded frontend Cypress end-to-end tests from a single smoke test to covering 90% of all critical frontend user flows.
- Documented all critical user flows throughout the platform in Airtable, categorizing and outlining user steps for each action, increasing efficiency by helping align stakeholders, product, engineering, support, and QA around this single resource.
- Assisted with customer technical issues as a liaison between customers and engineers solving over 250 tickets.

<u>Compass Inc.</u> Los Angeles, CA

Customer Experience Manager | Product Expert

Dec. 2018 - Mar. 2021

- Managed customer experience and product adoption for over 250 Real Estate agents, enabling them to leverage cutting-edge solutions consisting of technology and software suites and company programs to facilitate business growth.
- Supervised a team tasked with formulating and designing Monthly Product Newsletters distributed to over 3000 agents, aiming to build product knowledge, drive adoption and meet company performance targets.
- Planned a multimedia action plan to accelerate Compass product penetration in the Southern California market, resulting in top NPS rankings on product usage in multiple categories nationwide for 2019.

EDUCATION

BA Economics - UCLA | Graduated Sept. 2015

- Member of Anderson School of Management Entrepreneurship Association (Only Undergrad at UCLA admitted)
- Social Entrepreneurship Academy winner for Non-Profit Idea & Business Plan
- Member of Bruin Entrepreneurs Club
- Residential Advisor & Office Assistant for 2 years
- UCLA Radio Co-Marketing Director and DJ

Full-Stack Sofware Engineer Certificate - App Academy | Graduated Sept. 2021

- 24-week, 1000-hour immersive, and intensive full-stack software engineering program with less than a 3% acceptance rate.
- Coursework included: Object-Oriented Programming, REST, Systems Design, Coding Best Practices, Data Structures

Entrepreneur and Business Management Program - The Power MBA

- A complete business program and MBA alternative, learning concepts, tools, and methodologies from global business leaders such as founders and executives from Youtube, Netflix, Tesla, Airbnb, Whole Foods, Red Bull, Spotify, & more.
- Coursework includes Business Model Innovation, Testing Business Ideas & The Lean Startup, Business & Marketing
 Strategies, Leadership, Entrepreneurship & Fundraising, Finance & Accounting, HR & Talent Management, and more.

SKILLS

Product Management, Business Development, UX/UI Mock-up and Design, Marketing Strategies, Training and Facilitation, Javascript, Python, React, Redux, Express, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, SQL, CSS, Cypress, Git, Docker, Heroku, Node.js, Object Oriented Programming, RESTful API Design, Test Driven Development

ENGINEER PROJECTS

SHOULD I? (Python / Flask / SQLAlchemy / React / Redux / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Social media, polling web app that allows users to post poll questions with options and receive votes from other users.

- Implemented conditional React rendering to support both text and images as poll options so each could be visually represented and interacted with differently.
- Constructed a unidirectional data flow architecture with a single application-level state object to prevent mutated state and data collision, and to ensure reliable DOM rendering.
- Engineered a seamless one-click voting experience using Flask and React/Redux technologies, capable of creating, modifying, and deleting votes in response to user selection within the DOM.

STAYQUAINT (Javascript / Express / Sequelize / React / Redux / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Booking and reviewing web app for quaint, low-scale inns, cabins, and bed and breakfasts inspired by Airbnb.

- Built modular React components and modals to allow for flexible expansion and added features.
- Implemented data schema with a new lodging form that creates four new instances in four different tables and renders those needed elements without refreshing using Redux.

TABLETALK (Python / Flask / SQLAlchemy / React / Redux / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Restaurant reservation and social meetup web app allowing users to reserve and share their table inspired by OpenTable.

- Engineered platform to support two different user types, one for general users and one for businesses, with different account authentication, signup, and different web experiences including a conditionally rendered Navbar.
- Comprehensive database schema with 11 data tables utilizing many-to-many, one-to-many, and one-to-one relationships.

GOODTUNES (Javascript / Express / Sequelize / PUG / HTML / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Music discovery, managing and reviewing web app to help find your next best listen inspired by GoodReads.

- Connected PostgreSQL backend to the <u>Discogs API</u> to access an extensive database of artists, albums, and data to increase application utility and experience.
- Implemented a search bar using an Express backend with the <u>Discogs API</u> to improve user experience by making all albums in the Discogs database accessible throughout the application.